Nishant Suthar

M.Tech (Structural Design), A.M.ASCE

Civil and Structural Design Engineer with more than 5 years of experience in construction and structural design industry. Skilled in 3D Analytical Modeling, Structural Analysis and Design, Site Coordination, Documentation, Quality Assurance and Quality Control. Good Team Member & Standardization and Lead with Excellent Business Communication Skill. Dedicated to assign work, committed and reliable team member with positive attitude, always ready to take additional responsibilities.

E-mail:

Cell:

(416) 720-3811

Address:

112 - 30 Denton Avenue. Scarborough, ON, Canada. M1L 4P2

Linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/ nishant-suthar-6b593563/

Software Skills

Proficient

ETABS

SAFE

STAAD RCDC

AutoCAD

MS Office

SketchUp

Working Knowledge

STAAD Pro

Professional Capabilities

nishantmsuthar@gmail.com Strong background in structural engineering with wide exposure in analysis, design, detailing. Coordination with architects, all service providers, site, vendors and clients to carry out job. Completed various projects within tender quantities and in time.

> Structural Design experience in low-rise as well as high-rise residential. commercial, institutional, hospital and industrial buildings.

> Design of various RC and Posttension structures including conventional slabs & beam systems, flat slab systems, retaining wall, water retaining structures, industrial buildings and load bearing structures.

Preparation of structural bill of quantities and design report for tender work.

Ensuring compliance to design code standards, preparation of documents.

Attending client as well as design reviewer meetings. Getting approval of design documents and drawings from consultants / client.

Checking design v/s tender quantities before releasing the drawings.

Acting as an engineer coordinator for both operating job and tender job for various projects.

Frequent site visit during operating job, providing technical support / alternate design solutions to field engineers for the site problems.

Professional Work Experience

1.	Freelance Structure Design Engineer	(Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018)
	Ahmedabad, India.	

(Oct. 2015 - Nov. 2017)

PNL Engineering Consultants Pvt. Ltd. 2. Ahmedabad, India Position: Senior Structural Design Engineer

Ducon Consultants Pvt. Ltd. 3. (June 2013 - Sept. 2015)

Ahmedabad, India

Position: Structural Design Engineer

Education

1.	Master of Technology (M.Tech) in Structural Design	(2011 - 2013)
	CEPT University, Ahmedabad, India.	,

2 Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) in Civil Engineering (2006 - 2010)BVM Engineering College, V.V. Nagar, India.